Finding Aid for the John Clough Papers, circa 1959-2002
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Articles and papers by other authors, 1960-2000, IV.; Folders 72-368
  - Douthett, Jack, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 161)
    Boolean rings.
  - Douthett, Jack, November 1992 (Box 9, Folder 162)
    Circular distribution and measurements.
  - Douthett, Jack, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 163)
    Combinatorial properties of diatonic scale theory. Lecture notes
  - Douthett, Jack, undated (Box 9, Folder 164)
    Floor functions and maximally even sets and configurations.
  - Douthett, Jack, undated (Box 9, Folder 165)
    Formal mathematical intervallic notation.
  - Douthett, Jack, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 166)
    Inversion graphs.
  - Douthett, Jack, undated (Box 9, Folder 167)
    Iterated symmetry and the dynamics of voice leading.
  - Douthett, Jack, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 168)
    Me and music.
  - Douthett, Jack, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 169)
    P-relations. Addressed to Richard Cohn
  - Douthett, Jack, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 170)
    Pn-relations and scale theory.
  - Douthett, Jack, undated (Box 9, Folder 171)
    A perceptual approach to the metastructure of music.
  - Douthett, Jack, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 172)
    Pitch-class techniques, the pure fifth, and the East Indian grama family.
  - Douthett, Jack, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 173)
    Set properties of the series type used in Webern's Concerto for Nine Instruments, op. 24.
  - Douthett, Jack, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 174)
    3-dimensional tiling. 29 October 1997
  - Douthett, Jack, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 175)
    The twin primes problem and musical scales and chords (MP, CV, and twin primes).
  - Douthett, Jack, July 1996 (Box 9, Folder 176)
    The 2-dimensional antiferromagnetic Ising model.
  - Douthett, Jack, 1991-1996 (Box 9, Folder 177)
    [Wheels and maximally even sets]. Pencil ms., 5 June 1991. Typescript, 26 June 1996
  - Douthett, Jack and Block, Steven, undated (Box 9, Folder 178)
    Vector products and intervallic weighting.
  - Douthett, Jack and Entringer, Roger and Krantz, Richard, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 179)
    Tuning and continued fractions.
  - Douthett, Jack and Entringer, Roger and Mullhaupt, Andrew, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 180)
    Musical scale construction: the continued fraction compromise.
  - Douthett, Jack and Krantz, Richard, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 181)
    Construction and interpretation of equal-tempered scales using frequency ratios, maximally even sets, and P-cycles, In Journal of the Acoustical Society of America 107:5, May 2000
  - Douthett, Jack and Krantz, Richard, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 182)
    Energy extremes and spin configurations for the one-dimensional antiferromagnetic Ising model with arbitrary-range interaction, In Journal of Mathematical Physics 37:7, July 1996
  - Douthett, Jack and Krantz, Richard, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 183)
    A measure of the reasonableness of equal-tempered musical scales.
  - Douthett, Jack, Krantz, Richard and Doty, Steven D., 1997 (Box 9, Folder 184)
    Maximally even sets and the devil's staircase phase diagram for the one-dimensional Ising antiferromagnet with arbitrary-range interaction.
  - Dubiel, Joseph, undated (Box 9, Folder 185)
    Function, explanation, and interpretation.
  - Dugger, Ed, July 27 1990 (Box 9, Folder 186)
  - Dunne, Edward, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 187)
    Pianos and continued fractions. Paper presented at American Mathematical Society Meeting, January 10 1999
  - Engebretsen, Nora, December 1994 (Box 9, Folder 188)
    Some comments on the generation of certain scales with multiple constraints. Notes from John Clough, David Clampitt, and Engebretsen; article itself not included. Originally in folder with residual notes for Scales, sets, and interval cycles: a taxonomy.
  - Erlich, Paul, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 189)
    Tuning, tonality, and twenty-two-tone temperament. With correspondence, 15 items
  - Forte, Allen, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 190)
    Pitch-class set genera and the origin of modern harmonic species, In Journal of Music Theory 32:2, Fall 1988
  - Foulkes-Levy, Laurdella, undated (Box 9, Folder 191)
    LFB: Diatonic theory notes.
  - Foulkes-Levy, Laurdella, undated (Box 9, Folder 192)
    Three categories of chord connection and their interactions with harmonic activity and musical form.
  - Fraenkel, Aviezri S., 1969 (Box 9, Folder 193)
    The bracket function and complementary sets of integers, In Canadian Journal of Mathematics, 1969
  - Fuller, Sarah, undated (Box 9, Folder 194)
    Examples for Fuller: "Defending the Dodecachordon". Written by Clough
  - Gamer, Carlton, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 195)
    Deep scales and difference sets in equal-tempered systems. American Society of University Composers: Proceedings of the annual conference. II (1967). With accompanying notes by Clough
  - Gamer, Carlton, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 196)
    Et setera: some temperamental speculations, In Music Theory: special topics, 1981
  - Gamer, Carlton, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 197)
    Some combinatorial resources of equal-tempered systems, In Journal of Music Theory 11:1, Spring 1967
  - Gamer, Carlton, Roeder, David W., and Watkins, John J., 1985 (Box 10, Folder 198)
    Trapezoidal numbers, In Mathematics Magazine 58:2, March 1985
  - Gamer, Carlton and Wilson, Robin J., 1983 (Box 10, Folder 199)
    Musical block designs, In Ars combinatorial 16-A, 1983
  - Gauldin, Robert, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 200)
    The cycle-7 complex: relations of diatonic set theory to the evolution of ancient tonal systems, In Music Theory Spectrum 5, Spring 1983
  - George, Thomas F., 1991 (Box 10, Folder 201)
    Clusters and microstructures.
  - George, Thomas F., undated (Box 10, Folder 202)
    Derivation of the model
  - George, Thomas F. and Jelski, Daniel A., 1988 (Box 10, Folder 203)
    Clusters: link between molecules and solids, In Journal of Chemical Education 65, October 1988
  - George, Thomas F., Jelski, Daniel A. and Wu, Z. C., 1987 (Box 10, Folder 204)
    Vibrational motions of Buckminsterfullerene, In Chemical Physics Letters 137:3, 12 June 1987
  - George, Thomas F., Wang, Youqi, Lindsay, D. M., and Beri, A. C., 1987 (Box 10, Folder 205)
    The Hückel model for small metal clusters. I. Geometry, stability and relationship to graph theory, In Journal of Chemical Physics 86:6, 15 March 1987
  - George, Thomas F., Wang, Youqi, and Lindsay, D. M., 1987 (Box 10, Folder 206)
    The Hückel model for small metal clusters. II. Orbital energies, shell structures, ionization potentials, and extrapolation to the bulk limit, In Journal of Chemical Physics 86:6, March 15 1987
  - George, Thomas F., Wang, Youqi, and Lindsay, D. M., 1990 (Box 10, Folder 207)
    The Hückel model for small metal clusters. IV. Orbital properties and cohesive energies for model clusters of up to several hundred atoms, In Journal of Cluster Science 1:1, March 1990
  - Gollin, Edward, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 208)
    Crystallographic space lattices … Tonnetz. Figures for paper presented at Buffalo Music Theory Symposium, July 18-19, 1997.
  - Gollin, Edward, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 209)
    An interesting dihedral group, its automorphisms, and transformations in Bartók's "Minor seconds, major sevenths". Paper presented at New England Conference of Music Theorists, 6 April 1997
  - Gollin, Edward, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 210)
    Transformational spaces and metaphorical journeys in some Schubert Lieder.
  - Gordon, Carolyn and Webb, David, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 211)
    You can't hear the shape of a drum, In American Scientist 84, January-February 1996
  - Graham, R. L., 1973 (Box 10, Folder 212)
    Covering the positive integer by disjoint sets of the form …, In Journal of Combinatorial Theory 15, 1973
  - Grmela, Sylvia, 2000-2004 (Box 10, Folder 213)
    Dissertation material on Kurtág
  - Grmela, Sylvia, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 214)
    Messiaen's Pièce pour piano et quatuor à cordes.
  - Grmela, Sylvia 1997 (Box 10, Folder 215)
    Paper presented at Society for Music Theory meeting, 1997
  - Guy, Richard K., 1981 (Box 10, Folder 216)
    Unsolved problems in number theory.
  - Guy, Richard K., 1992 (Box 10, Folder 217)
    Western number theory problems. 19 December 1992, 22 December 1992
  - Haack, Joel K., 1991 (Box 10, Folder 218)
    Clapping music - a combinatorial problem, In College Mathematics Journal 22, 1991
  - Hanson, Howard, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 219)
    The projection and interrelation of sonorities in equal temperament from Harmonic Materials of Modern Music
  - Hauptmann, Moritz, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 220)
    The nature of harmony and metre (1888). Photocopy of Da Capo Press reprint, 1991
  - Heinemann, Stephen, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 221)
    Boulez's elegant operation: pitch-class set multiplication in Le marteau sans maàt;re
  - Herron, Amy J., 2000 (Box 10, Folder 222)
    Exploring melodic patterns in diatonic and chromatic music. With correspondence
  - Herstein, I. N., 1964 (Box 10, Folder 223)
    Topics in algebra. Photocopy of p. 1-38
  - Hook, Julian L., 1999-2001 (Box 10, Folder 224)
    Correspondence between Hook, Jack Douthett, and John Clough, 5 items
  - Hook, Julian L., 2000 (Box 10, Folder 225)
    Cross-type transformations, GIS homomorphisms, and generalized transposition and inversion. Paper presented at Indiana Graduate Theory Association Symposium, Feb. 25, 2000
  - Hook, Julian L., 1 May 1997 (Box 10, Folder 226)
    Equal-tempered approximations to intervals by the method of continued fractions.
  - Hook, Julian L., 1999-2000 (Box 10, Folder 227)
    Uniform triadic transformations: A Unified theory of triadic transformations. Dissertation proposal, with correspondence
  - Hughes, J. Robin, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 228)
    Correspondence, 2 items
  - Hyde, Martha, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 229)
    Dodecaphony: Schoenberg (op. 33b). From Early Twentieth Century Music, 1993
  - Hyer, Brian, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 230)
    Reimag(in)ing Riemann, In Journal of Music Theory 39:1, Spring 1995
  - Isaacson, Eric J., 1992 (Box 11, Folder 231)
    Similarity relations in music analysis. Paper presented at Society for Music Theory Meeting, 1992
  - Ishihara, Paul and Knapp, Michael, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 232)
    Basic Z12 analysis of musical chords, In Tools for Teaching, 1993
  - Jefferis, Jim, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 233)
    Analytically rich Klumpenhouwer networks: their properties and conditions. Class paper for MUS613, 16 December 1996
  - Johnson, Timothy, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 234)
  - Johnson, Timothy, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 235)
    Foundations of diatonic theory: a supplemental text for introductory music theory classes. With review by Clough
  - Jones, Mari Reiss, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 236)
    Music as a stimulus for psychological motion: Part I. Some determinants of expectancies, In Psychomusicology 1:2, 1981
  - Jung, Jiyoung, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 237)
    The new approach respect to contour theory in Deut by Milton Babbitt. Notes for class presentation, 10 December 1999
  - Kárpáti, János, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 238)
    Alternative structures in Bartók's Contrasts, In Studia Musicologica Academiae Scientiarum Hungaricae 23, 1981
  - Kleeman, Emily, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 239)
    Number theoretical relationships between mathematics and music.
  - Klein, Michael, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 240)
  - Klein, Michael, undated (Box 11, Folder 241)
    Chopin's Etude in C, op. 10/1: text, context, and intertext.
  - Klumpenhouwer, Henry, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 242)
    Essay on Lewin's and Hyer's use of transformations derived from Riemann's work, In Music Theory Online, 1994
  - Kochavi, Jonathan, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 243)
    Musical groups
  - Kochavi, Jonathan, undated (Box 11, Folder 244)
    Sequences
  - Kopp, D., 1992 (Box 11, Folder 245)
    A system of pentatonic organization in a Debussy prelude. Paper presented at Society for Music Theory Meeting, Oct. 16, 1992
  - Kreyszig, Walter, 1996-1998 (Box 11, Folder 246)
    Correspondence, 8 items
  - Krumhansl, Carol L., 1995-1997 (Box 11, Folder 247)
  - Krumhansl, Carol L., 1987 (Box 11, Folder 248)
    General properties of musical pitch systems: some psychological considerations. From Harmony and Tonality, 1987
  - Krumhansl, Carol L., undated (Box 11, Folder 249)
    Perceptual analysis: tension and topic in music.
  - Krumhansl, Carol L., 2000 (Box 11, Folder 250)
    Rhythm and pitch in musical cognition, In Psychological Bulletin 126:1, 2000
  - Krumhansl, Carol L., 1990 (Box 11, Folder 251)
    Tonal hierarchies in atonal and non-Western tonal music; Music cognition: theoretical and empirical generalizations. Chapters 10 and 11 from the author's Cognitive Foundations of Musical Pitch
  - Krumhansl, Carol L. and Kessler, Edward J., 1982 (Box 11, Folder 252)
    Tracing the dynamic changes in perceived tonal organization in a spatial representation of musical keys, In Psychological Review 89:4, 1982
  - Kurth, Richard, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 253)
    A partition-lattice model of prolongation and progression in twelve-tone music.
  - Kurth, Richard, undated (Box 11, Folder 254)
    Schoenberg and combinatoriality: another perspective.
  - Lefkoff, Gerald, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 255)
    The complex functional fields in diatonic-tonal compositions.
  - Lekkas, Demetrios E., 1996 (Box 11, Folder 256)
    Correspondence and excerpt from book
  - Lerdahl, Fred, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 257)
    Cognitive constraints on compositional systems. From Cognitive Processes in Music
  - Lewin, David, 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 258)
    Correspondence with Clough, Richard Cohn, David Clampitt
  - Lewin, David, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 259)
    Formal theory of generalized tonal functions, In Journal of Music Theory 26:1, Spring 1982. With correspondence
  - Lewin, David, undated (Box 11, Folder 260)
    Interesting cases of the interval function between pitch-class sets X and Y.
  - Lewin, David, undated (Box 11, Folder 261)
    Transformational considerations in Schoenberg's Opus 23, number 3.
  - Lindley, Mark, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 262)
    Mersenne on keyboard tuning, In Journal of Music Theory 24:2, Fall 1980
  - Lindley, Mark, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 263)
    A systematic approach to chromaticism. With correspondence, 2 items
  - Makeig, Scott, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 264)
    Affective versus analytic perception of musical intervals. From Music, Mind, and Brain
  - Mandell, Arnold J., Selz, Karen A., and Giangrande, Janice, undated (Box 12, Folder 265)
    Eigenfunction themes and ergodic variations in jazz and classical music.
  - Mathews, M. V., Pierce, J. R., and Roberts, L. A., 1987 (Box 12, Folder 266)
    Harmony and new scales. From Harmony and tonality: Papers given at a seminar organized by the Music Acoustics Committee of the Royal Swedish Academy of Music, 1987
  - Mavromatis, Panayotis and Williamson, Virginia, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 267)
    Similarity of pitch class sets: a perceptual study. Paper presented at Society for Music Theory Meeting, 30 October 1997
  - Mazzola, Guerino and Zahorka, Oliver, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 268)
    Rubato: the open standard workstation for analysis and performance of music. With correspondence regarding Mazzola's planned lecture in Buffalo and a Perspectives of New Music article by John Roeder: A MaMuTh achievement, about Mazzola's work.
  - McCartin, Brian J., 1998 (Box 12, Folder 269)
    Prelude to musical geometry, In College Mathematics Journal 29:5, 1998
  - McLaren, Brian, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 270)
    General methods for generating musical scales.
  - McLaren, Brian, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 271)
    Postings on modern theory and microtonality.
  - McLaren, Brian and Darreg, I., 1991 (Box 12, Folder 272)
    Biases in xenharmonic scales, In Xenharmonikon 13, Spring 1991
  - Mead, Andrew, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 273)
    Webern, tradition, and "composing with twelve tones …".
  - Meredith, David, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 274)
    Tonal scales and graph theory. With correspondence, 3 items, between Clough, Meredith, and Jack Douthett
  - Morris, Robert D., 1994 (Box 12, Folder 275)
    Equivalence and similarity in pitch and their interaction in Pcset theory. Paper presented at Society for Music Theory Meeting, 1994
  - Morris, Robert D., 1998 (Box 12, Folder 276)
    Sets, scales, and rhythmic cycles: a classification of talas in Indian music. Examples for paper presented at Society for Music Theory Meeting, 1998
  - Morris, Robert D., undated (Box 12, Folder 277)
    Voice-leading spaces.
  - Morris, Robert D., undated (Box 12, Folder 278)
    Why weight? Pitch-class duplications in twelve-tone polyphony.
  - Myerson, Gerry, 1987-1990 (Box 12, Folder 279)
    Correspondence, 9 items
  - Neal, Jocelyn, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 280)
    Graphic representation of trichord-partition symmetries in selected hexachords. Paper presented at Music Theory Society of New York State, 1997
  - Nolan, Cathy, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 281)
    Appendix: Interval cycles generalized. With correspondence, 2 items
  - O'Connell, Walter, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 282)
    Tone spaces. With correspondence
  - Olds, C. D., 1963 (Box 12, Folder 283)
    Continued fractions. Photocopy of 5th printing, 1963
  - Olivastro, Dominic, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 284)
    Object lessons: state of grace, In The Sciences, May/June 1991
  - Oña, Erik, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 285)
    Preliminary remarks on voice leading pattern classes.
  - Park, Jae-Sung, 17 October 1990 (Box 12, Folder 286)
  - Payne, Maribeth Anderson, on behalf of Schirmer Books, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 287)
  - Peck, Robert W., 2001 (Box 12, Folder 288)
  - Peifer, David, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 289)
    An introduction to combinatorial group theory and the word problem, In Mathematics Magazine 70:1, February 1997
  - Peles, undated (Box 12, Folder 290)
    Partial orderings as compositional prototypes.
  - Polansky, Larry, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 291)
    More on morphological mutation functions, recent techniques and developments.
  - Pressing, Jeff, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 292)
    Cognitive isomorphisms between pitch and rhythm in world musics: West Africa, the Balkans and Western tonality, In Studies in Musici 17, 1983
  - Quinn, Ian, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 293)
    Fuzzy transposition of pitch sets. Paper presented at Society for Music Theory Meeting, 2 November 1996
  - Quinn, Ian, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 294)
    On relations, similarity, and similarity relations. Paper presented at Society for Music Theory Meeting, 1997
  - Rahn, Jay, 1991-1999 (Box 12, Folder 295)
    Correspondence, circa 20 items
  - Rahn, Jay, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 296)
    An advance on A Theory for all music: at-least-as predicates for pitch, time and loudness; figures and appendix.
  - Rahn, Jay, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 297)
    Asymmetrical ostinatos in sub-Saharan music: time, pitch, and cycles reconsidered, In In Theory Only 9:7, March 1987
  - Rahn, Jay, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 298)
    "Chinese harmony" and contemporary non-tonal music theory, In Canadian University Music Review 19:2, 1999
  - Rahn, Jay, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 299)
    Constructs for modality, ca. 1300-1500, In Canadian Association of University Schools of Music Journal 8:2, Autumn 1978
  - Rahn, Jay, undated (Box 12, Folder 300)
    Counting pairs that match or differ, and the gestalt principle of similarity in music.
  - Rahn, Jay, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 301)
    The isomorphism of pitch and time. From A Theory for All Music, 1983
  - Rahn, Jay, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 302)
    Perceptual aspects of tuning in a Balinese gamelan angklung for North American students, In Canadian University Music Review 16:2, 1996
  - Rahn, Jay, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 303)
    Recent diatonic theory and Curwen's tonic sol-fa method: formal models for a kinesic-harmonic system, In Proceedings of the Third Triennial ESCOM conference, June 1997
  - Rahn, Jay, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 304)
    Restricted relational richness and musical analysis, In Journal of Comparative Literature and Aesthetics 8:1-2, 1985
  - Rahn, Jay, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 305)
    Structure and frequency in South Indian melas, In Proceedings of the Saint Thyagaraja music festivals, 1981
  - Rahn, Jay, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 306)
    Turning the analysis around: Africa-derived rhythms and Europe-derived music theory, In Black Music Research Journal 16:1, Spring 1996
  - Rahn, Jay and Xue-Qing, Xu, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 307)
    "Chinese harmony" and contemporary non-tonal music theory.
  - Randolph, John, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 308)
    On Lewin's generalized interval systems.
  - Ravenstein, Tony van, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 309)
    Optimal spacing of points on a circle, In Fibonacci Quarterly, February 1989
  - Reiner, David L., 1985 (Box 13, Folder 310)
    Enumeration in music theory, In The American Mathematical Monthly 92:1, January 1985
  - Roeder, John, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 311)
    A calculus of accent.
  - Roeder, John, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 312)
    Issues of representation in the analysis of atonal music, In Proceedings of the First Workshop on Artificial Intelligence and Music, 1988
  - Roeder, John, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 313)
    A Prolog program for music segmentation, In Musicus 1:2, December 1989
  - Roeder, John, undated (Box 13, Folder 314)
    Second thoughts: pretension and form in Fauré's Prelude, op. 103, no. 9.
  - Roeder, John, undated (Box 13, Folder 315)
    Semiotic aspects of music analysis.
  - Roeder, John, undated (Box 13, Folder 316)
    Voice leading as transformation.
  - Rogers, John, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 317)
    Some properties of non-duplicating rotational arrays.
  - Rogers, John and Mitchell, Barry, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 318)
    A problem in mathematics and music, In American Mathematical Monthly 75, 1968. With notes
  - Roiter, Robert, 10 November 1983 (Box 13, Folder 319)
    Set transformation geometry.
  - Rothenberg, David, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 320)
    A model for pattern perception with musical applications Part II: The information content of pitch structures, In Mathematical Systems Theory 11, 1978
  - Rowell, Lewis, 1994-1997 (Box 13, Folder 321)
  - Rowell, Lewis, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 322)
    The pentatonic dialect(s) of India.
  - Rudin, Cynthia, 15 December 1998 (Box 13, Folder 324)
    The complement theorem and its applications.
  - Samplaski, Artie, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 324)
    Axiomatic derivations of scales: a comparative review/critique of three approaches.
  - Santa, Matthew, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 325)
    Hexatonic and nonatonic systems in late nineteenth century music.
  - Santa, Matthew, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 326)
    Modular sets and modular set types.
  - Schat, Peter, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 327)
    On harmony and tonality, In Key Notes 19, 1984
  - Schat, Peter, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 328)
    The tone clock: or, the zodiac of the twelve tonalities, In Key Notes 17, 1983
  - Scott, Damon and Isaacson, Eric J., undated (Box 13, Folder 329)
    The interval angle: a similarity measure for pitch-class sets.
  - Shepard, Roger N. and Jordan, Daniel S., 1984 (Box 13, Folder 330)
    Auditory illusions demonstrating that tones are assimilated to an internalized musical scale, In Science 226, December 1984
  - Slawson, Wayne, undated (Box 13, Folder 331)
    Subaggregate braids.
  - Sloan, Donald, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 332)
    Fuzzy set theory, fuzzy measures, and their application to resemblance theories in music. Handouts for paper presented at Society for Music Theory Meeting, 3 November 1995
  - Slottow, Stephen, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 333)
    A Ruggles compositional model and its unfoldings.
  - Smith, Charles J., 1995 (Box 13, Folder 334)
  - Smith, Charles J., undated (Box 13, Folder 335)
    Appreciation for John Clough. Two versions
  - Smith, Charles J., undated (Box 13, Folder 336)
    Diatonic sequences. Lecture notes
  - Smith, Charles J., 1996 (Box 13, Folder 337)
    Tonal models of music. ch. 2.6, 5, 6.
  - Smith, J. David, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 338)
  - Snell, James, 19 October 1990 (Box 14, Folder 339)
    Mathematics and music.